所以你就是时间变异管理局 勤劳勇敢的工作人员？
LOKI: So, you're part of the TVA's courageous and dedicated workforce?
是的
Yes.
你是时间守护者创造的？
You were created by the Time-Keepers?
没错
Correct.
前情提要
为我工作的分析师又不止你一个
RAVONNA: You're not the only analyst working for me.
但是我是不是你最喜欢的那个？
But, would you say,  maybe, I'm your favorite one?
附身这一招挺聪明
LOKI: Enchantment is a clever trick.
我就需要创造一个他们记忆中的幻想
SYLVIE: I have to create a fantasy from their memories.
那个时间变异管理局的年轻士兵 她就是个地球上的普通人
That young soldier from the TVA,  she was just a regular person on Earth.
时间控制器储存的所有末日里 这是最糟糕的
Of all of the apocalypses saved on that TemPad, this is the worst!
没人能活下来
No one makes it off here!
咱们还有多长时间？
LOKI: How long do we have?
12个小时左右 这里的情况只会越来越糟
SYLVIE: Twelve hours or so.  Things down hereare only gonna get worse.
敬世界末日
To the end of the world.
巨龙冲向宫殿
Dragon swoops towards the palace,
女武神飞驰而至 击败了巨龙 拯救了阿斯加德
the Valkyrie flies over,  defeats the dragon, and saves Asgard.
时间犯在那里
There's our Variant.
根据时间守护者授予的权力
On the authority of the Time-Keepers,
我以侵犯神圣时间线的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
重置它
Reset it.
等等
Wait!
时间变异管理局 永恒常相伴
不要 不要
MAN: No! No!
救救他
Help him!
下一个案件
Next case!
-下一个案件 -来了
-Next case!  -Right here!
《洛基》
他们怎么说的？你还好吗？
What'd they say? Are you okay?
不 莫比乌斯 我不好
No, no, Mobius. I'm not.
即便不出任何差错
Under the best of circumstances,
站在时间守护者面前也很有压力
it's jarring to stand before the Time-Keepers.
更不用说现在一团糟了
And this is not the best of circumstances.
是的 但是这不能怪你
Yeah, but they can't blame you.
他们就是这么做的
They can and do.
时间犯来到了这里
The Variant was right here.
如果她找到了时间守护者呢？
What if she got to the Time-Keepers?
我知道 但是她没找到
I know. But she didn't.
是的 但是她逃跑了
No. But she got away.
和另一个时间犯一起 他能来这还是我帮你申请的许可
Along with the Variant that I got you permission to bring in here.
你知道保持时间线稳定有多难吗？
Do you have any idea how impossible it is to keep the timeline stable?
能保护我们免于全面毁灭的 只有时间守护者
The Time-Keepers are all that stand between us and full-scale calamity.
我很高兴他们站咱们这边
And I'm glad they're on our side.
但是如果他们想让我 找到洛基和那个时间犯
But if they want me to find Loki and the Variant,
我需要和追捕者C-20交谈
I need access to Hunter C-20.
抱歉 那是不可能的
I'm sorry, but that's impossible.
咱们找到她的时候 她一直在说 〝那是真的 那是真的〞
Look, when we found her,  she kept saying, "It's real. It's real. "
一遍又一遍地重复 我得弄明白那是什么意思
Over and over.  I need to find out what that meant
还有她和那个时间犯在一起的时候 看到了什么其它的东西
and what else she saw when she was with the Variant.
我知道有规矩 但如果她能提供信息…
Look, I know there's protocol,  but she could have information. . .
她死了 莫比乌斯
She's dead, Mobius!
什么？怎么死的？
What? How?
那个时间犯 她附身在C-20身上 扰乱了她的心智
The Variant, she enchanted C-20,  scrambled her mind.
我不理解 她看上去没事啊 她看上去挺好的
I don't get it. She seemed okay.  She seemed fine.
一开始是这样的
RAVONNA: At first, yes.
但是到这里的时候 她已经不能说话了
But by the time she got in here,  she could barely speak.
之后恶化的速度越来越快
The decline was steeper after that.
-我不知道 什么… -没人知道
-I didn't know. What. . .  -Nobody does.
我们也不想让其他人恐慌
We don't want people to panic.
这件事你能保密吗？
Can I trust you to keep that between us?
当然可以
Of course. Yes.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
只要那些时间犯仍然在逃
Every moment those Variants are out there,
我们就有危险
we're all in danger.
找到他们
Find them!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我记得阿斯加德
I remember Asgard.
不是很清楚 但是有印象
Not much, but I remember.
我的家乡 我的人民 我的生活
My home, my people, my life.
宇宙想要挣脱束缚 所以它创造了混乱
The universe wants to break free,  so it manifests chaos.
就比如我 出生就是诡计女神
Like me being born the Goddess of Mischief.
只要神圣时间线出现了明显的分支
And as soon as that created a big enough detour from the Sacred Timeline,
时间变异管理局就会出现 消除我所在的现实 然后把我抓起来
the TVA showed up, erased my reality,  and took me prisoner.
我当时只是个孩子
I was just a child.
我逃跑了
I escaped.
我偷了一个时间控制器 然后很长时间里一直在逃 不堪回首
Stole a TemPad and I ran for a long,  long time, which really sucked.
我所到的任何地方和任何时间 都会出现关连事件
Everywhere and every-when I went,  it caused a nexus event.
就会引起注意
Sent up a smoke flare.
因为我就不该存在
Because I'm not supposed to exist.
最后我找到了藏身之处
Until, eventually,  I figured out where to hide.
那就是我长大的地方
And so that's where I grew up,
无数个世界的终结
the ends of a thousand worlds.
现在
Now. . .
这就是我的葬身之处
. . . that's where I'll die.
什么都没有 长官
ANALYST 1: There's nothing, sir.
放大关连阈值也没有吗？
MOBIUS: Even with the magnified nexus threshold?
有任何小动静 都会触发警报
That one should be setting off alarms if somebody steps on the wrong leaf.
无论他们在哪 我觉得都很难活下来
ANALYST 2: Wherever they are,  I'm not sure anything survives.
别小看他们 你在罗克斯卡特看到什么了吗？
Yeah. Don't underestimate them.  You see anything down at Roxxcart?
他们消失了
They're gone.
他们在时间里穿行 谋划着下一次屠杀
Leaping across time,  plotting their next massacre.
C-20有什么消息吗？
Any news on C-20?
没有
No.
我们得找到他们
We need to find them.
我们会的
We will.
快了
SYLVIE: Not long now.
你觉得洛基之所以成为洛基
Do you think that what makes a Loki a Loki
是不是我们注定要失败的宿命？
is the fact that we're destined to lose?
不是
LOKI: No.
我们可能会失败
We may lose.
有的时候惨不忍睹
Sometimes painfully.
但是我们死不了
But we don't die.
我们能活下来
We survive.
你不是活下来了嘛
I mean, you did.
时间变异管理局抓到你的时候 你只是个孩子
You were just a child when the TVA took you,
但是你几乎打败了 那个号称统治时间秩序的组织
but you nearly took down the organization that claims to govern the order of time.
你单枪匹马做到了
You did it on your own.
你比他们更厉害 你是最棒的
You ran rings around them. You're amazing!
我们发现了些东西
We've got something.
锁定现世光环
ANALYST 1: Temporal lock.
好吧 这可不是什么小动静
Okay, that's not someone stepping on the wrong leaf.
你们见过这样的分支吗？
You ever seen a branch like that?
从来没有
No.
-说呀？ -说什么？
MOBIUS: Well?  LOKI: Well, what?
我知道你肯定憋了一肚子话
I know you got some quip you're dyin' to say.
我没有 我没什么好说的
I don't have a quip.  I've got nothing to say.
不会吧
Come on.
话说回来 我的警卫应该和她一样多 你这是在侮辱我
By the way, I should have an equal amount of security. This is insulting!
你控制不了你自己
You just can't help yourself.
-你背叛了我 -是你背叛了我
-You betrayed me!  -You betrayed me!
-成熟点 -你成熟点
-Grow up!  -You grow up.
我忽然发现你根本不是什么诡计之神
MOBIUS: You know, it occurred to me that you're not really the God of Mischief.
又来了
LOKI: Oh, here it comes.
一介凡人对神的无知的羞辱
The folksy, dopey insult from the folksy dope.
那我是什么？自我陷害之神？ 背后捅刀子之神？
What am I? The God of Self-Sabotage, yeah?  The God of Back-Stabbing?
你就是个混蛋 是个差劲的朋友
Just kind of an asshole and a bad friend.
你自己去好好反思吧 好吧 准备好了
Yeah, chew on that for a little bit.  All right. It's ready.
这是什么？
What is this?
你会明白的
You'll see.
-莫比乌斯 -好吧 等等 让他说
-Mobius!  -Okay. No, no, no, let him,
看看这个走投无路的骗子还有什么花样 说吧
one last desperate trick from the desperate trickster. Go ahead.
时间变异管理局在欺骗你
The TVA is lying to you.
把他扔进去
Put him in.
不
什么？
What?
真的吗？
Seriously?
你
You.
希芙
Sif.
你这个狼狈为奸、胆小懦弱、可悲之极的蠕虫
You conniving, craven, pathetic worm.
-这是你干的 -什么？
-You did this.  -What?
你就活该一个人 永远如此
LOKI: Ow. I hope you know you deserve to be alone and you always will be.
好吧
All right.
这是个糟糕回忆的监牢吗？太老套了。
A bad memory prison? How quaint.
LOKI: Ow!
我受到了些惩罚
我记得特别清楚之后去干什么了
I remember exactly what I did after that.
我去美美地泡了个澡
I went and had a nice, hot bath
一杯酒下去 这件事就彻底忘了
and a glass of wine,  and I never thought about it again,
因为就是好玩而已
because it was just a bit of fun.
你
-SIF: You.  -Huh?
你这个狼狈为奸、胆小懦弱、可悲之极的蠕虫 这是你干的
You conniving, craven, pathetic worm.  You did this.
等等
Hang on. Ow.
你就活该一个人 永远如此
I hope you know you deserve to be alone and you always will be.
等等
Just. . .
时间循环 妙极了
Time loops. How lovely.
你
You.
你这个狼狈为奸、胆小懦弱、可悲之极的蠕虫
You conniving, craven, pathetic worm.
好吧 好吧 希芙 等一下
Okay. Okay, Sif. Hang on.
不 你听好了 你就活该一个人…
No, you hear this.  You deserve to be alone. . .
永远如此 好吧 我明白了
And I always will be.  All right, I get it.
听着 你是一个过去场景的重构
Listen. You are a reconstruction of a past event
是掌控时间的那个组织创造出来的
created by the organization that controls all of time.
你得相信我 然后帮我逃出去 好吗？
So you need to trust me and you need to help me escape. Yeah?
好吧 很好
Okay, good.
可悲之极
Pathetic.
嘿
Hey.
你不是应该在审讯那个洛基时间犯吗？
Shouldn't you be interrogating the Loki Variant?
他正在时间监牢里被感化呢
He's softening in the Time Cell,
在他受教育的时候 我想和另一个时间犯谈谈
but while he marinates, I thought maybe I'd interview the other Variant.
不用了 继续去审问你的洛基 弄清楚那个关连分支是怎么回事
Oh, no. Just stick with your Loki and figure out what that nexus spike was.
我知道 但是我觉得如果能审问他们两个 我能更快找到答案
I know, but I think I can get there faster if I work 'em both together.
你说过我们都有各自的角色 我的角色就是…
You said we have a part to play,  and the part I play. . .
不必了 她太危险了
Absolutely not. She's just too dangerous.
太危险了？不是吧 拉芙娜 我就是干这个的
Too dangerous? Come on, Ravonna.  This is what I do.
那我就是干这个的
And this is what I do.
谁也别想和那个时间犯交谈
Nobody speaks with that Variant.
我觉得如果背后有主使 不太可能是洛基
I mean, if there's a mastermind here,  I don't think it's Loki.
很好
Good.
那让他老实交代应该不难
Then he should be the easiest to break.
搞定你的洛基 弄清楚那个分支是怎么回事
Work your Loki and figure out what caused that spike.
时间守护者盯着呢 莫比乌斯
Time-Keepers are watching, Mobius.
他们一直盯着呢 〝搞定你的洛基 搞定你的洛基〞
They're always watching.  "Work your Loki, work your Loki. "
都快成我的口头禅了
That ought to be my mantra.
你还好吗？
You all right?
她在里面吗？
-Is she in there?  -Mm-hmm.
他们不会轻饶了她 是不是？
They don't go gently, do they?
你不是应该在审讯那个时间犯小伙伴吗？
Aren't you supposed to be interrogating your Variant pet?
我出来活动活动
Just stretching my legs.
咱们抓过克里人、泰坦巨人 还有吸血鬼
You know, we brought in Kree,  Titans, vampires.
为什么这两个没爹没妈的半神这么难对付？
Why is it the two orphan demigods are such a pain in the ass?
把另外那个带来不是你的主意嘛
And yet it was your idea to bring in another one.
也不光是我的主意吧
I'm happy to share credit for that idea.
莫比乌斯？
Mobius?
你在那里的时候洛基说什么了吗？
Did Loki say anything while you were in there?
是的 他说时间变异管理局在欺骗我
Yeah. He said the TVA is lying to me.
为什么要问这个？
Why?
这是我的职责
Just doing my job.
你
-SIF: You.  -
你这个狼狈为奸、胆小怯懦…
You conniving, craven. . .
-希芙 希芙 -可悲之极的蠕虫
-Sif. Sif.  -. . . pathetic worm.
求求你了 别再来了 拜托 求求你了
Please, please, no more.  Please, I beg you.
我是个坏人 我知道 我真的是个坏人
I'm a horrible person.  I get it. I really am.
我剪了你的头发 因为我觉得好玩
I cut off your hair because I thought it'd be funny.
其实一点也不好玩
And it's not.
Uh. . .
我渴望别人的关注
I crave attention. . .
因为我是…
because I'm. . .
我是个…我是个自恋狂
I'm a. . . I'm a narcissist.
我觉得…
And I suppose it's. . .
这是因为我害怕孤独
It's because I'm scared of being alone.
你就是孤独一人 永远如此
You are alone and you always will be.
好吧 洛基
Okay, Loki.
能聊聊了吗？
You ready to talk?
花里胡哨的技术
Fancy technology.
威胁式的审讯策略
Threatening interrogation tactics.
感觉好像是昨日重现啊
Seems you and I are in a loop of our own.
自从上次以后发生了很多事啊
Well, there's been a lot of water under the bridge since then.
当然了
LOKI: Certainly has.
你说时间变异管理局在欺骗我 你接着说
Okay, you said the TVA is lying to me.  Go ahead.
还是说那就是蟑螂的求生本能？
Or is that just a cockroach's survival mechanism kicking in?
让我从这出去 别再对我动手 我就告诉你
Let me out of this place,  stop beating me up, and I'll tell you.
果然是蟑螂 明白了
Cockroach. Got it.
你为那个时间犯工作多久了？
How long have you been working for the Variant?
我？为她工作？拜托
Me? Working for her? Please.
如果你不是为她工作 那你们是什么？ 搭档吗？
If you're not working for the Variant,  what is it? You're partners?
当然不是
Absolutely not.
她很难伺候 让人头疼
She's difficult and irritating,
而且她一直在打我
and she tries to hit me all the time.
肯定不是搭档 不是
No. Not partners, no.
我也觉得你不该有搭档
Yeah, I guess you don't do partners.
当然 除非对你有好处
Unless, of course, it benefits you,
然后你计划在某一刻背叛他们
and you intend to betray them at some point.
这是达到目的的手段 莫比乌斯
It was a means to an end, Mobius.
欢迎来到现实世界
Welcome to the real world.
现实里 我们为了达到目的不择手段
Down there, we're awful to get what we want.
我用得着一个王子告诉我 现实世界是什么样的吗？
Now I gotta have a prince tell me how the real world works?
你给我讲讲 拉曼迪斯的关连事件是怎么回事
Why don't you just tell me what caused the nexus event on Lamentis?
我再说一遍
Let me say this again.
我不会告诉你的
I'm not going to tell you
不然你会立刻把我抛弃然后裁剪掉
just so you can turn around immediately afterwards and prune me.
咱这天儿是真往死了聊啊
I guess we've reached a dead end then.
好吧 到此为止
Okay, it's over.
我会怀念咱们拌嘴的时候的
I'm going to miss these little tete-a-tetes.
我也一样
LOKI: Me, too.
你是玩跳棋的 老莫比乌斯可是下象棋的
One guy playing checkers, you,  old Mobius playing chess,
替我问希芙女士好
but, yeah, give my regards to Lady Sif.
什么…不 什么？不
What. . . No. What? No, no, no.
拜托 别…好吧 你等等 等等
Please, not. . .  Well, just wait, wait, wait.
怎么着？
Yeah?
当然是我在操控这一切
Of course it was me pulling the strings all along.
她很久以前来阿斯加德找我
She came to me on Asgard a long time ago
然后她带我去了其中一个末日
and then she took me to one of her apocalypses
在那里我们一起制定了计划
and that's where we hatched our plan together.
计划是？
Which is?
计划进展得很顺利 谢谢
Coming along very nicely, thank you.
那个时间犯呢？
MOBIUS: And the Variant?
不重要 她就是个棋子
Doesn't matter. She's a pawn.
有一件超级大的事要发生了
Something very, very big is gonna happen.
到那个时候 我就会抛弃她
And when it does, I'll dispose of her.
那用不着你自己动手了
Well, we saved you the trouble there.
她已经被裁剪了
She's already been pruned.
-假设我真的放了你 -等等
-So assume I do set you free.  -Hang on, wait.
-你刚才说什么？ -什么？假设我真的放了你
-What'd you just say?  -What? Assume I do set you free.
那个时间犯 她死了？
LOKI: The Variant. She's gone?
是的 她杀了我们两个人
Yeah. Not before she took out two of ours.
她本来要被送进时间监狱的 然后她挣脱了
Yeah, she was going to her Time Cell, broke free.
追捕者B-15出手裁剪了她
Hunter B-15 stepped in, popped her.
你应该给追捕者B-15写个感谢信
So you might want to fire off a thank you note to Hunter B-15,
因为看来你才是更高级的洛基
because it looks like you're the superior Loki.
我本来是在她身上下注的 但是赛马就是这样
I would've bet on her,  but that's what makes a horse race.
总算摆脱了
Good riddance.
-有什么好笑的？ -不是吧
-What's so funny?  -Come on.
看看你的眼睛 你喜欢她
Look at your eyes. You like her.
-什么？ -你喜欢她 她喜欢你吗？
-What?  -You like her. Does she like you?
-她被裁剪了吗？ -怪不得你对
-LOKI: Was she pruned?  -No wonder you have no clue
拉曼迪斯的关连事件一点头绪都没有
what caused the nexus event on Lamentis.
你们两个人在互相爱慕
Both of you are swooning over each other.
-跟我说实话 -那可是末日
-LOKI: Tell me the truth.  -It's the apocalypse.
相同本体的两个时间犯
Two Variants of the same being,
特别是你 居然会有这种 病态的、扭曲的浪漫关系
especially you, forming this kind of sick,  twisted romantic relationship.
这太混乱了 这会打破现实
That's pure chaos.  That could break reality.
我的现实已经碎了一地了
It's breaking my reality right now.
真是惊天地泣鬼神的自恋狂
What a incredible seismic narcissist.
你爱上你自己了
You fell for yourself.
她叫希尔维
Her name was Sylvie.
希尔维
Ah, Sylvie.
挺好
Lovely.
怎么拼？是IE结尾还是I结尾？
How do you spell that?  Is that with an I-E or just an I?
她还活着吗？
Is she alive?
暂时吧
For now.
渗透时间变异管理局 一直都是你们的计划吗？
And was infiltrating the TVA,  was that always sort of the grand plan?
我们的利益是一致的
Our interests are aligned.
-推翻时间守护者？ -也许他们就应该被推翻
-MOBIUS: Overthrowing the Time-Keepers?  -Maybe they need to be overthrown.
-我应该抽你一耳光 -莫比乌斯 听着
-I ought to box your ears.  -LOKI: Mobius, listen.
如果希尔维说的是真的 这个地方在影响我们所有人
If what Sylvie told me about this place is true, it affects all of us.
开始了 你在过去10分钟里 已经说了50个谎了
Here we go. Now, you've already told me about 50 lies in the past 10 minutes.
-我没有说谎 -我觉得你现在就在说谎
-I'm not lying.  -Now, I'm supposed
-让我相信你的女朋友 -这是事实
-to believe your girlfriend.  -It's the truth.
-她不是我的女朋友 -你愿意叫她什么随你便
-She's not my girlfriend.  -Whatever you want to call her.
那个你如痴如狂一见倾心的女性自我
What, your female self that you have some demented crush on. . .
你们都是时间犯
You're all Variants!
所有在时间变异管理局工作的人都是
Everyone who works at the TVA.
时间守护者并没有创造你们 他们把你们从时间线上绑架了
The Time-Keepers didn't create you.  They kidnapped you from the timeline,
然后消除了你们的记忆
and erased your memories.
她可以通过附身进入那些记忆
Memories she can access through enchantment.
所以在这一切以前 你有自己的过往 也许你有自己的家庭 自己的生活
So before this, you had a past,  maybe you had a family, a life.
说的不错
Nice try.
真漂亮 你们俩还真是天生一对
That was good. You two, what a pair!
天啊 令人难以置信 你们所到之处 只有死亡和毁灭
Gosh! Unbelievable. Wherever you go,  it's just death, destruction,
货真价实的世界末日
the literal ends of worlds.
我要结束这个案子了
Well, I'm gonna have to close this case now,
因为我不需要你了
'cause I don't need you anymore.
或者用你的说法 咱们的利益不一致了
Yeah, or as you might say,  our interests are no longer aligned.
你知道吗 这个地方所有的骗子里
You know, of all the liars in this place,
这里的骗子可不少 你是最大的骗子
and there are a great many,  you're the biggest.
为什么？因为我骗你女朋友死了？
Why? 'Cause I lied about your girlfriend?
不是 那个我心存感激 我是说你对自己的欺骗
Oh, no. That I can respect.  I mean, the lies you tell yourself.
一网打尽？ 删除以确认
开门
Open the door.
你好 我不知道你叫什么
Hello. . . Oh, I don't know.
你的名字是个数字 我在这边看不清
Your name's a number.  Can't read it from here.
跟我来
Come with me.
莫比乌斯？
Mobius?
好吧
Oh, yeah.
-你还好吗？ -我挺好的
-You okay?  -Yep, I'm good.
-结案了 -是的
-Case closed.  -Yes.
干杯
Cheers.
-干杯 -别再为这些事烦心了
-Cheers.  -To putting all this behind us.
阿门
Amen.
随便让你选 你会去什么时间什么地方？
If you could go anywhere, anytime,  where would it be?
我可以去任何地方任何时间
I can go anywhere, anytime.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
为什么不让我审讯希尔维？
Why wouldn't you let me interrogate Sylvie?
-希尔维？ -那个时间犯 洛基这么称呼她
-Sylvie?  -The Variant, that's what Loki calls her.
为什么你不让我审问她？
Why wouldn't you let me,  you know, question her?
我告诉过你 不能冒险让她再跑掉
I told you,  we couldn't risk her escaping again.
她跑不掉的
She wouldn't have escaped.
另一个时间犯 在你第一次审问的时候就跑了 是不是？
The other Variant got away during your first interrogation, didn't he?
来吧 时间线上的任意时间地点 你去哪？
Come on. Anywhere and anytime on the timeline. Where'd you go?
我就想在这里陪着你一起工作
I like being here now, with you,  doing the work.
好吧
Fine.
我得到了时间守护者的命令
I received word from the Time-Keepers.
他们要亲眼看着这个时间犯被裁剪
They want to personally oversee the Variant's pruning.
他们要求你也在场
And they want you there, too.
终于等到这一刻了 太棒了
It's about time. Great.
你第一次注意到C-20有问题是什么时候？
When. . . When did you first notice what was going on with C-20?
莫比乌斯 你怎么了？
Mobius, what is going on with you?
-没怎么 -我们成功了
-Nothing.  -We did it.
-我知道 -时间守护者很高兴
-I know.  -The Time-Keepers are happy.
-太棒了 -任务完成了
-It's great.  -Mission accomplished.
任务完成了 只是她看上去挺好的…
Mission accomplished.  It was just that she seemed fine when I. . .
我看见她的时候 她有点恐惧 不过还好
When I saw her.  I mean, a little freaked, but fine.
她很快就不好了
Well, she quickly wasn't fine.
-好吧 -好吧
-Okay.  -Okay.
C-20？那个时间犯？
C-20? The Variant?
你问这些问题 到底想说什么？
All these questions,  what are you getting at?
我不知道…
I don't know. I. . .
感觉有些不对劲
Something just seems a little off.
好吧 你想知道真相吗？
Fine. You want the truth?
我在试着保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
正常情况下你会这样和人交谈吗？没问题
Would you normally interview someone like that? Yeah.
但是这个时间犯让我很害怕
But the Variant scares the hell out of me,
我可不想看到你出什么问题
and I didn't want to see anything happen to you.
C-20完全疯了
C-20 lost her mind.
她到最后连一句话都说不出来
She couldn't even form words by the end.
我可不能接受这样的事 发生在你或其他人身上
I just couldn't deal with that happening to you or anyone else.
这是你想知道的吗？
Is that what you wanted to hear?
是的 如果是事实的话
Yeah, if it's the truth.
你在这些洛基身上花了太多时间了
You've been spending too much time with Lokis.
是的
Yeah.
我确实在这些洛基身上花了太多时间了
I definitely have been spending too much time with Lokis.
咱们在这里的工作很重要
What we do here matters.
我知道
I know.
我们在为神圣时间线战斗的同时
When we're out there fighting for the fate of the Sacred Timeline
我们也在为我们自己而战
we're also fighting for this. For us.
我们是经历时间考验的战友 我们是永恒的盟友
Friends against time, allies to the end.
你和我一样 看到过所有的一切 所以你知道的
You've seen all of existence, same as me.  So, you know,
像我们这样的友谊并不常见
friendship like ours is uncommon.
也值得我们为之奋斗
And worth fighting for.
神圣时间线也是如此
Same as the Sacred Timeline.
说得好
It was a good speech.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道我是你最喜欢的分析师 承认这一点有那么难吗？
I knew I was your favorite analyst.  Was that so hard to admit?
你打算怎么处理那个战利品？ 要摆在哪里？
What are you gonna do with that trophy?
你说得对
-Oh!  -Where's that gonna go? You're right.
我想想
Let's see.
RAVONNA: Uh. . .
放在这怎么样？
How's that?
完美 你都快没地方放了
Looks perfect.  You're running out of room there.
好吧 回头见
All right, I will see you later on.
喝一杯就走了？
One drink?
-我喝了两杯 不是吗？ -莫比乌斯
-MOBIUS: I had two, didn't I?  -Mobius!
这可是你职业进阶的大好机会 你确定你没事吗？
This is a career case.  You sure you're okay?
我就是累了 对付这些洛基太累了
I'm just exhausted,  dealing with all these Lokis.
好吧
Fair enough.
咱们把这件事做个了断
Let's finish this.
永恒
For all time.
常相伴
Always.
咱们回头见 谢谢你的酒
I'll see you up there.  Thanks for the drink.
好吧 你想要公平决斗 我尊重你
Fine. You wanted a fair fight.  I respect that.
罗克斯卡特
你在我脑子里的时候 我看到了些东西
When you were in my head, I saw something.
你对我做了什么？
What did you do to me?
我让你看到了来时间变异管理局之前的人生
I showed you your life before the TVA.
那是骗人的 那不是真的
That's a trick. It's a deception.
-不 那是真的 -我是时间守护者创造的
-No, it's not.  -I was created by the Time-Keepers.
不是 我不能创造记忆
No. I can't create memories.
我只能利用已经存在的记忆
I can only use what's already there.
时间守护者夺走了你们的人生
The Time-Keepers took your lives from you.
夺走了你们所有人的人生
From all of you.
你们都是时间犯
You're Variants.
咱们是一样的
We're the same.
让我看看
Show me.
我看上去很快乐
I looked happy.
现在怎么办？
What now?
正在搜索
追捕者C-20 状况：已死亡
发现档案…任务简报 44Y10 已加密
黑文山 阿拉巴马州 罗克斯卡特
你没听我说话 我在那里
You're not hearing me. I was there.
我看到的是真的 这是我去过的地方
This was real, what I saw.  This is a place that I've been.
这不是时间变异管理局 这是我的记忆
This wasn't the TVA. This was a memory.
我住在那里 我去过那个酒吧 我有朋友
I lived down there. I went to that bar.  I had friends.
我在神圣时间线上有自己的人生
I had a whole life on the Sacred Timeline.
-冷静一下 -〝冷静一下〞？我是个时间犯
-INTERROGATOR: Calm down.  -"Calm down"? I'm a Variant.
你也一样 这里的所有人都一样
So are you.  So is every single person in this place.
我要结束这一切
I'm ending this.
我听过了 我听过一千遍了
I've heard it once,  I've heard it a thousand times.
〝你 你这个狼狈为奸、胆小怯懦 可悲之极的蠕虫 这是你干的〞
"You. You conniving, craven,  pathetic worm. You did this. "
对吗？
Right?
-你在干什么？ -消耗时间
-What are you doing?  -Passing the time.
你关心她吗？
Do you care about her?
希尔维？我不确定这个词用得是否准确
Sylvie? I'm not sure if it's the right word.
-咱们刚才已经聊过这个了 -住口
-We've covered this back in there.  -Shut up!
你真的觉得你就活该一个人吗？
Do you really think you deserve to be alone?
-洛基 -你让我住口的
-Loki!  -You told me to shut up.
你真的觉得你就活该一个人吗？
Do you believe you deserve to be alone?
-我不知道 -你最好快点想清楚
-I don't know.  -You better figure it out quick,
因为你们两个造成的关连事件
because the nexus event the two of you caused,
不管是什么关系 会让这个地方崩溃
whatever that connection is,  can bring this whole place down.
-所以咱们最好明白… -〝咱们〞？
-So we better understand. . .  -"We"?
你发誓她没有给追捕者C-20植入那些记忆？
Do you swear she didn't implant those memories in Hunter C-20?
莫比乌斯 不可能 我相信她
Mobius, no. I believe her.
所以我得相信两个洛基说的话？
So, I just have to trust the word of two Lokis?
你觉得相信朋友说的话怎么样？
How about the word of a friend?
关于时间变异管理局 你是对的
You were right, about the TVA.
你从一开始就是对的
You were right from the beginning.
如果你想要救她 就得相信我
And if you wanna save her,  you need to trust me.
可以吗？
Can we do that?
-可以 -好的
-Yes.  -MOBIUS: Okay.
你可以成为任何你想成为的人
You could be whoever,  whatever you wanna be,
甚至是个好人
even someone good.
我的意思是 没准曾经有人让你做个坏人呢
I mean, just in case anyone ever told you different.
我觉得你拿了我的东西
I think you have something of mine.
对 我大老远跑到这里 才发现我拿错了
Yeah, I got all the way down there before I even realized I picked up yours.
怎么了？
What's going on?
有什么问题 拉芙娜？
What's the problem, Ravonna?
你知道让我选 我想去哪里吗？
You know where I'd go if I could go anywhere?
我要去我真正来自的地方
Wherever it is I'm really from.
对 在时间变异管理局之前我生活的地方
Yeah, wherever I had a life before the TVA came along.
没准我有个摩托艇呢
Maybe I had a jet ski.
那就是我想做的
That's what I'd like to do.
-到处骑摩托艇 -裁剪掉他
-Just riding around on my jet ski.  -Prune him.
在电梯那里等着我
Wait for me at the elevator.
刚才谁和她在一起？
Who was in here with her?
抱歉 长官 B-15坚持要进来
Sorry, ma'am, B-15 insisted.
发出警报 抓住追捕者B-15
Put out an alert for Hunter B-15.
她也被时间犯策反了
She too has been compromised by the Variant.
你还好吗？
You okay?
接下来他们两个交给我了
I've got them from here.
你记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
我记得
I do.
你想对我说什么 时间犯？
What do you wanna say to me, Variant?
我的关连事件是什么？
What was my nexus event?
你为什么把我带来？
Why did you bring me in?
这重要吗？
What does it matter?
夺走我的人生 导致所有这一切
It was enough to take my life from me,  lead to all of this.
肯定很重要
Must have been important.
所以 是什么？
So, what was it?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
仁慈的时间守护者
RAVONNA: Gracious Time-Keepers,
如我承诺的那样 我带来了时间犯
as promised, the Variants.
经历了几番波折后
After all your struggle,
你们终于站在了我们面前
at last, you've arrived before us.
在你们迎来结局之前 有什么要说的吗 时间犯？
What do you have to say for yourselves before you meet your end, Variants?
这就是你们把我们带到这里的原因吗？
Is that the only reason you brought us here?
杀了我们？
To kill us?
我已经记不清我被杀过多少次了 所以请便
I've lost track of the number of times I've been killed, so go ahead.
动手吧
Do your worst.
你的虚张声势对我们毫无威胁 时间犯
You and your bravado are no threat to us, Variant.
不 我觉得你们不是这么想的
Oh, no, I don't think you believe that.
我觉得…
-I think. . .  -
我觉得你们很恐惧
I think you're scared.
不 时间犯 你太令人失望了
No, Variant. You're nothing but a cosmic disappointment.
-删除掉他们 -不 我还没说完呢
-Delete them.  -No, I'm not done with you yet.
永恒
For all time.
常相伴
Always.
保护时间守护者
Protect the Time-Keepers!
帮我个忙？
LOKI: A little help here?
接着
Here.
来啊
Come on.
这一次我来做个了断
This time I finish the job.
你也是时间守护者的子嗣 希尔维
You're a child of the Time-Keepers too, Sylvie.
-我们可以谈谈 -好啊？
-We can talk.  -SYLVIE: Oh, yeah?
等等
Wait.
不要
Don't.
假的
Fake.
没有灵魂的机器人
Mindless androids.
它永远不会停止
It never stops.
那是谁创造了时间变异管理局？
Then who created the TVA?
我原以为这就是终点了
I thought this was it.
希尔维…
Sylvie. . .
不用安慰我了
Not another pep talk, please.
不 我有些事要告诉你
No, I have to tell you something.
我们会弄明白的
We will figure this out.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
因为…
Because, uh. . .
在拉曼迪斯的时候
Well, back on Lamentis. . .
我从来没有经历过
This is new for me. Um. . .
什么？
What?
你要干什么？
What is it?
动手吧
Do it.
不
No.
你要把一切都告诉我
You're gonna tell me everything.
If the sun
Should tumble from the sky
If the sea
根据漫威漫画改编
Should suddenly run dry
If you love me
Really love me
Let it happen
I won't care
If it seems
That everything is lost
I will smile
And never count the cost
If you love me
Really love me
Let it happen
Darling, I
Won't care
Shall I catch a shooting star?
Shall I bring it where you are?
If you want me to, I will
You can set me any task
I'll do anything you ask
If you'll only say you love me still
When at last
Our life on earth is through
I will share
Eternity with you
If you love me
Really love me
Let it happen
I won't care
漫威影业出品
I you love me
《洛基》
Really love me
Let it happen
Darling, I. . .
这是赫尔海姆吗？
Is this Hel?
我死了吗？
Am I dead?
还没有
VOICE: Not yet.
但你要是不跟我们走 就死定了
But you will be unless you come with us.
字幕翻译： 虫二